<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shader on Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/tags/shader/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shader on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 11:59:37 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/tags/shader/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Create Stylized GPU Instancing Billboard Grass Without Creating Position Buffer in URP</title>
      <link>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/create-stylized-gpu-instancing-billboard-grass-without-creating-position-buffer-in-urp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 11:59:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/create-stylized-gpu-instancing-billboard-grass-without-creating-position-buffer-in-urp/</guid>
      <description>Environment Unity 2021.3.16f1&#xA;URP 12.0&#xA;Prerequisite Basic knowledge of C# and Shader programming (HLSL).&#xA;GPU Instancing GPU instancing is a technique that allows you to draw multiple copies of the same mesh using a single draw call. It is basically normal forward rendering pipeline but skipping the Vertex Specification stage.&#xA;Graphics.DrawMeshInstancedIndirect The first step to create multiple millions of grass is to properly call the GPU to draw so, a.k.a. draw call.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recreating the Rain Drop Effect in The Legend of Zelda: TOTK</title>
      <link>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/recreating-the-rain-drop-effect-in-the-legend-of-zelda-totk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 23:50:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/recreating-the-rain-drop-effect-in-the-legend-of-zelda-totk/</guid>
      <description>Environment Unity 2021.3.16f1&#xA;Universal Render Pipeline 12.0.0&#xA;Introduction I recently finished The Legend of Zelda: Tears of the Kingdom. To me as an indie game developer, it felt like a text book of open world game design. I had a lot of fun playing it and I learned a lot from it.&#xA;One of the things I noticed is the rain drop effect that react to the uppper edges of the scene.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layer-based Screen-Door Transparency Effect using Unity URP 12</title>
      <link>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/layer-based-screen-door-transparency-effect-using-unity-urp-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 22:54:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.yaotian-huang.com/en/ta/layer-based-screen-door-transparency-effect-using-unity-urp-12/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, I will be discussing how I implemented a Screen-door transparency effect in Unity using URP 12. This effect is used to simulate the look of a transparent object by applying Bayer Ordered Dithering to the semi-transparent object. This effect can be used in games to give the player a better view of the character even when the character is coverd by obstacles.&#xA;How it works You can think of this effect as using a sharp pencil to poke a dense grid of holes onto a paper to reveal the objects behind the paper.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
